OKOLIE CHUKWUKA ALBERT



Contact

Address:

No. 34, Badore Street Ajah, Lagos State.

Phone:

+2349038185240

Email:

www.chukypedro15@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

Linked.com/In/okolie-chukwuka

GitHub:

github.com/okoliechukywuka

Language:

English

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am experience data scientist with a demonstrated history of working in the E-commerce and Tobacco industry. Skilled in Business Planning, Data Science, Machine learning, Web development, and Microsoft excel. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including HTML5, OOP, JavaScript, CSS, MySQL, Python, JQuery and Bootstrap. Exercises strong leadership and teambuilding abilities with an emphasis on successful employee training programs and customer relations.

Skill Highlights

- Data Science
- Data Scraping
- Statistical Testing
- Excel and Microsoft Power B I
- Python/Django
- Data Analysis

- Machine Learning(Supervised & Unsupervised)
- Business Executive Development
- MS Word and PowerPoint
- Backend Developer(SQLite Python & Django)
- Html/CSS/JavaScript/Bootstrap/JQuery

Experience

<u>Great Brands Nigeria Limited/ British American Tobacco - Lagos, Nigeria:-11/2017 to 09/2018</u>

Mobile Data Analyst, Lagos

- Analysis and Visualization of Data Through the Use Of Microsoft Excel and Power B. I.
- Preparation of Template the use of Power Pivot, Excel Formulas and Data Analysis ToolPak.
- Building a Predictive Model in Excel with Monte Carlo simulations, linear regression, and Logistic regression.
- Using Data Analysis ToolPak in Excel to perform statistical calculations on Anova, Binomial Distribution, Poisson Distribution, Normal Distribution Chi-Square, T-testing/Hypothesis testing, Standard Error and Normal Distributions.

Moan Technology

Data Scientist 11/2018 to 06/2019:

- Extraction Of Data From Various Websites through the use of Python Web Scraper and Beautiful Soup.
- Analyzing and Visualization of bulky and Messy Data through the use of Python libraries like Numpy, Pandas, Seaborn, Matplotlib and Scipy.
- Building a Predictive Model through the use of Machine Learning libraries like Seaborn and Statsmodels.
- Predicted stock price 35% better than traditional figures.
- Maintained and Managed website MS SQL server.

 I have successfuly built a face recognition model that helps to identify celebrities just by their image using deep learning libraries like Keras and Tensor Flow.

Freelancer 2/2018-to date:

 As a freelancer on Fiverr, Freelancer and PeopleperHour I have successfully completed over 100+ I.T related project, this projects cut across Web Development, Web Scraping, Machine learning and Data Analysis.

Educational Background

University of Benin, B.sc Industrial Physics	2012 - 2016
National Youth Service Discharge Certificate	2016 - 2017
New Hope Secondary School SSCE O Level Result Obtained	2003 - 2009
Primary School Certificate	1995 - 2002

HOBBIES

Reading, discovering new things, meeting people, music, Football and playing chessboard games.